Shav Vimalendiran

∞ futureproof

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I decided to pursue a career in software development (having graduated with a degree in Chemical Engineering) after I tried my hand at using Python while training my own StyleGAN to artificially generate artwork. As someone who loves to <u>paint</u>, I value creativity and attention-to-detail in everything I do, and Software engineering is the perfect creative outlet that values and leverages these skills, but also the analytical, interpersonal, technical and problem-solving skills I have honed during my time as an engineer. In the future I aspire to work with the latest tech, helping to innovate and create high-quality and revolutionary apps, projects, products and services. Aside from programming and painting, I love to dance, hit the gym, complete obstacle courses, and manage my investment portfolio.

SUMMARY

I obtained a Master's degree (First Class Honours) in Chemical Engineering (MEng) from Imperial College London this year. Following my graduation, I decided to begin training with future proof to upskill as a Full Stack Developer in order to kick-start my career in Software Engineering.

The transferrable skills I've gained as part of my previous experiences relevant to the tech industry are numerous; as a Chemical Engineer I'm trained to use a structured approach for chemical process synthesis – such a methodical approach is powerful when writing code. The engineering projects I've completed to date as part of a team, generating good designs quickly and solving problems at hand, have also prepared me for effectively and quickly delivering projects as part of a dev team. Working at a small but fast-paced company in the tech field last summer and holding positions of responsibility such as Head of Events (responsible for hosting and organising events such as club nights, balls and shows) has further sharpened my management, organisation and interpersonal communication skills; all vital parts of working in a dev team.

I'm now looking forward to transitioning from coding as a hobby to becoming a valuable part of a team that builds innovative software products to meet user needs.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Futureproof | Software Engineer | June 2021 - September 2021

GitHub @ github.com/Shavvimal

- 13-week bootcamp covering the main areas of web development, including JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Databases, Cyber Security, TDD, SQL, Node/Express and Python.
- Pair programming projects utilised a collaborative Git workflow to develop applications

Splento | Internship | Visual Tech Start-up | June 2020 - July 2020

- Launched and promoted Virtual Reality technology in San Diego following market and competitor analysis
- Built and drove traffic to product pages using Search Engine Optimisation (SEO), PR Campaigns and Marketing skills
- Utilised written communication and created 360 VR videos in Premiere Pro for the purposes of content marketing
- Built upon transferable sales skills by listening, negotiating, persevering, communicating and being attentive.

Pharmacy Asda | Part time work | June 2019 - March 2020

- Interpersonal skills were utilised to handle patients, requiring patience & diplomacy to resolve conflicts with respect
- Worked effectively and efficiently in a very high-pressured environment.

EDUCATION

Imperial College London | Oct 2017 - June 2021

MEng Chemical Engineering, IChemE Accredited - First Class Honours

Queen Elizabeth's Boys School, Barnet | September 2010-2017

A-Level - Biology (A*), Chemistry (A*), Maths (A*), Physics (A), Further Maths AS (a) **GCSE-** 11 A*'s (including Maths, English and Sciences), 1 A

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Core Stack

JavaScript - HTML - CSS

Testing

Jest – SuperTest – React Testing Lib Pytest

API's & Backend

Express.js - Node.js

Databases, Authentication & Cybersecurity

Node.js - MongoDB - Docker - SQL PostgreSQL - Bcrypt

UI

React - Redux - Webpack - Babel - JSX React Router - Tailwind CSS

Python

Python – Flask – Django – NumPy Pandas – TensorFlow – Keras - Pytorch

Other

MATLAB - Git - GitHub - LaTeX GAMS - Solidworks - Photoshop Illustrator - Premiere Pro - InDesign aws - GSAP - JWT Tokens